Painting Medium Format Photograph Collection
Yale University Arts Library
Painting Medium Format Photograph Collection
1900-2005
VRC 12
Yale University Arts Library
90.3
57 boxes
Collection consists of mounted black and white and color reproductions of paintings. Content varies from original photographic prints to reproductions from magazines and other published sources. Some sections have accompanying clippings folders.
Conditions Governing Access
These materials are stored offsite at the Library Shelving Facility. For access to the materials, please make a request at the Art & Architecture Library.
Arrangement
Organized alphabetically by country. Further subdivided by individual artist name.
Scope and Contents
Collection consists of mounted black and white and color reproductions of paintings. Content varies from original photographic prints to reproductions from magazines and other published sources. Some sections have accompanying clippings folders.
Painting; Photographs; Reproductions
- Ancient World (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous Artists., 5 (Box 1)
- Egypt (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous Artists., 10 (Box 1)
- Roman (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous Artists., 12 (Box 1)
- Early Medieval (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous Artists., 6 (Box 1)
- Miscellaneous Countries (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous Artists., 5 (Box 2)
- Austria (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous Artists., 2 (Box 2)
  - Klimt, G., 10 (Box 2)
- Britain
  - Miscellaneous Artists, A-M., 22 (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous Artists, N-Z., 16 (Box 3)
  - Blake, William., 10 (Box 4)
  - Constable, John., 5 (Box 4)
  - Gainsborough., 10 (Box 4)
- Flanders
  - Miscellaneous Artists, A-L., 12 (Box 5)
  - Miscellaneous Artists, M-Z., 20 (Box 5)
  - Borsch, Hieronymus., 8 (Box 6)
  - Breughel, Peter., 29 (Box 6)
  - Rubens, Peter Paul., 33 (Box 7)
  - Van Dyck, Sir Anthony., 12 (Box 8)
  - Van Eyck, Jan., 10 (Box 8)
  - Van Der Weyden, R., 8 (Box 8)
- France
  - Anonymous., 7 (Box 9)
  - Miscellaneous Artists, A-Z., 119
    - Augustin, Jean Baptiste Jacques, 1759-1804., 1 (Box 9)
    - Barraud, Francois, 1899-1934., 1 (Box 9)
    - Bastien-Lepage, Jules, 1848-1884., 2 (Box 9)
    - Boucher, Francois, 1703-1770., 5 (Box 9)
    - Boudin, Eugene, 1824-1898., 1 (Box 9)
    - Breton, Jules, 1827-1906., 1 (Box 9)
    - Buffet, Bernard, 1928-., 2 (Box 9)
    - Chaplin, Charles, 1825-1891., 1 (Box 9)
    - Chardin, Jean Baptiste, 1699-1779., 2 (Box 9)
    - Charonton, Equerrand, 1410-1461., 1 (Box 9)
    - Charpentier, Constance, 1767-1849., 1 (Box 9)
    - Chasseriau, Theodore, 1819-1856., 1 (Box 9)
    - Claude of Lorraine, 1600-1682., 1 (Box 9)
    - Clouet, Francois, 1486-1540., 2 (Box 9)
    - Colombe, Jean, XV C., 1 (Box 9)
    - Corneille de Lyon, Claude, 1500/5-1574., 1 (Box 9)
    - Courbet, Gustave, 1819-1877., 2 (Box 9)
    - Daubigny, Charles Francois, 1817-1878., 1 (Box 10)
    - Daumier, Honore, 1808-1879., 2 (Box 10)
    - Delaunay, Robert, 1885-1941., 1 (Box 10)
    - Derain, Andre, 1880-1954., 3 (Box 10)
    - Drouais, F. H., 1727-1775., 1 (Box 10)
    - Dufresne, Charles, 1876-1936., 1 (Box 10)
    - Dufy, Raoul, 1877-1953., 4 (Box 10)
    - Fantin-Latour, Henri, 1836-1904., 2 (Box 10)
    - Farestier, Amedee, XIX-XX C., 1 (Box 10)
    - Flandrin, Jean-Paul, 1811-1902., 2 (Box 10)
    - Fouquet, Jean, 1420-c.1480., 3 (Box 10)
    - Francais, Francois Louis, 1814-1897., 1 (Box 10)
    - Gericault, Theodore, 1791-1824., 1 (Box 10)
    - Gerome, Jean L., 1824-1904., 1 (Box 10)
    - Gleyre, M. C. G., 1806-1874., 2 (Box 10)
    - Gerimoux, Alexis, 1678-1733., 1 (Box 10)
    - Hubert, Robert, 1733-1808., 1 (Box 11)
    - Lancret, Nicolas, 1690-1743., 2 (Box 11)
    - La Tour, George Dumesnil de, 1600-1652., 1 (Box 11)
    - Le Brun, Charles, 1619-1690., 1 (Box 11)
    - Le Corbusier, 1887-1965., 1 (Box 11)
    - Lefevre, Robert, 1756-1830., 1 (Box 11)
    - Le Moyne, Fracois, 1688-1737., 2 (Box 11)
    - Le Nain, Louis, 1583/93-1648., 1 (Box 11)
    - Levy, Emile, XIX C.?, 1 (Box 11)
    - Loo, Louis Michel van, 1707-1771., 1 (Box 11)
    - Marquet, Albert, 1875-1947., 2 (Box 11)
    - Master of Moulins, 1455-1530., 1 (Box 11)
    - Master of St. Giles, XV C., 1 (Box 11)
    - Meissonier, J. L. E., 1815-1891., 1 (Box 11)
    - Moreau, Gustave, 1826-1898., 2 (Box 11)
    - Morisot, Berthe, 1841-1895., 1 (Box 11)
    - Natoire, Charles J., 1700-1777., 1 (Box 11)
    - Nattier, Jean-Marc, 1685-1766., 1 (Box 11)
    - Pater, J. B. F., 1695-1736., 1 (Box 11)
    - Poussin, Nicolas, 1594-1665., 2 (Box 11)
    - Prudhon, Pierre Paul, 1758-1823., 3 (Box 11)
    - Puvis de Chavannes, 1824-1898., 4 (Box 11)
    - Puy, Jean, 1876-1960., 1 (Box 11)
    - Raffaelli, Jean Francois, 1850-1924., 1 (Box 12)
    - Redon, Odillon, 1840-1916., 1 (Box 12)
    - Regnault, Henri, 1843-1871., 2 (Box 12)
    - Rigaud, Hyacinthe, 1659-1743., 1 (Box 12)
    - Robillard, H., XIX C.?, 1 (Box 12)
    - Roualt, Georges, 1871-1958., 4 (Box 12)
    - Rousseau, Henri, 1844-1910., 1 (Box 12)
    - Roux, Gaston-Louis, XX C., 1 (Box 12)
    - Salmson, XIX C., 1 (Box 12)
      Scope and Contents
      Also known as Barriere D'Alby.
    - Seurat, Georges, 1859-1891., 1 (Box 12)
    - Signac, Paul, 1863-1935., 3 (Box 12)
    - Simon, ?, XIX-XX C., 1 (Box 12)
    - Singier, Gustave, 1909-., 1 (Box 12)
    - Tissot, James Jacques, 1836-1902., 1 (Box 12)
    - Toulouse-Lautrec, Henri de, 1864-1901., 4 (Box 12)
    - Utrillo, Maurice, 1883-1955., 2 (Box 12)
    - Van Marcke, Emile, 1827-1890., 1 (Box 12)
    - Vasarely, Victor, 1908-., 1 (Box 12)
    - Vuillard, Edouard, 1867-1940., 2 (Box 12)
    - Walch, Charles, 1896-1948., 1 (Box 12)
    - Zao, Wou-ki, 1921-., 1 (Box 12)
  - Individual Artists, A-Z., 250
    - Bonnard, Pierre, 1867-1947., 8 (Box 13)
    - Cezanne, Paul, 1839-1906., 16 (Box 13)
    - Corot, Jean Baptiste Camille, 1796-1875., 8 (Box 13)
    - David, Jacques-Louis, 1748-1825., 4 (Box 13)
    - Degas, Edgar, 1834-1917., 32 (Box 14)
    - Delacroix, Eugene, 1798-1863., 4 (Box 14)
    - Fragonard, Jean-Honore, 1732-1806., 7 (Box 15)
    - Fresnaye, Roger de la, 1885-1925., 7 (Box 15)
    - Froment, Nicolas, active 1470-1490., 4 (Box 15)
    - Gauguin, Paul, 1848-1903., 20 (Box 15)
    - Greuze, Jean-Baptiste, 1725-1805., 5 (Box 16)
    - Ingres, Jean Auguste Dominique, 1780-1867., 22 (Box 16)
    - Manet, Edouard, 1832-1883., 15 (Box 16)
    - Matisse, Henri, 1869-1954., 40 (Box 17)
    - Millet, Jean-Francois, 1814-1875., 9 (Box 18)
    - Monet, Claude, 1840-1926., 17 (Box 18)
    - Pissarro, Camille, 1830-1903., 5 (Box 18)
    - Renoir, Pierre-Auguste, 1841-1919., 18 (Box 19)
    - Watteau, Antoine, 1684-1721., 9 (Box 19)
- Germany
  - Miscellaneous Artists, A-Z., 25 (Box 20)
    - Baegert, Derick, 1450-1520., 1 (Box 20)
    - Burckmair, Hans, ?., 1 (Box 20)
    - Corinth, Lovis, 1858-1925., 1 (Box 20)
    - Cranach, Lucas the Elder, 1472-1553., 2 (Box 20)
    - Holbein, Hans the Elder, c.1460-1524., 3 (Box 20)
    - Kulmbach, Hans von, c.1480-1522., 3 (Box 20)
    - Leibel, Wilhelm, 1844-1900., 1 (Box 20)
    - Lochner, Stefan, 1410-1451., 4 (Box 20)
    - Manuel Deutsch, Niklaus, c.1484-1530., 1 (Box 20)
    - Master of the Death of the Virgin Mary, active 1430-1440., 1 (Box 20)
    - Master of the Hausbuch, XV C., 1 (Box 20)
    - Pacher, Michael, c.1435-1498., 2 (Box 20)
    - Ratgeb, Jorg, 1480-1526., 1 (Box 20)
    - Rethel, Alfred, 1816-1859., 2 (Box 20)
    - Soest, Conrad von, active 1405-1422., 1 (Box 20)
  - Individual Artists, A-Z., 83
    - Durer, Albrecht, 1471-1528., 39 (Box 21)
    - Grunewald, Matthias, 1470-1530., 31 (Box 22)
      Includes a portfolio of unmounted pictures.
    - Holbein, Hans the Younger, 1457-1543., 13 (Box 23)
- Holland
  - Miscellaneous Artists, A-Z., 26 (Box 24)
    - Appel, Karel, 1921-., 1 (Box 24)
    - Battem, Gerard van, 1636-1684., 1 (Box 24)
    - Cuyp, Albert, 1620-1691., 1 (Box 24)
    - Dongen, Kees van, 1877-1968., 1 (Box 24)
    - Dou, Gerard, 1613-1675., 1 (Box 24)
    - Hanneman, Adriaen, c.1600-1671., 1 (Box 24)
    - Heyden, Jan van der, 1637-1712., 1 (Box 24)
    - Hobbema, Meindert, 1638-1709., 2 (Box 24)
    - Hooch, Pieter de, 1629-1684., 3 (Box 24)
    - Janssen, Cornelius, 1593-1664., 1 (Box 24)
    - Leyden, Lucas van, 1494-1533., 1 (Box 24)
    - Lievens, Jan, 1607-1674., 1 (Box 24)
    - Metsu, Gabriel, 1629/30-1667., 3 (Box 24)
    - Mieris, Frans, 1635-1681., 1 (Box 24)
    - Saenredam, Pieter, 1597-1665., 1 (Box 24)
    - Terborch, Gerard, 1617-1681., 2 (Box 24)
    - Velde, Illem van de the Younger, 1633-1707., 2 (Box 24)
    - Vermeer, Johannes, 1632-1675., 2 (Box 24)
    - Werff, Adriaen van der, 1659-1722., 1 (Box 24)
  - Individual Artists, A-Z., 83
    - Hals, Frans, 1580-1666., 5 (Box 25)
    - Rembrandt van Rijn, 1606-1669., 25 (Box 25)
    - Ruysdael, Jacob van, 1628-1682., 5 (Box 25)
    - Van Gogh, Vincent, 1853-1890., 48 (Box 26)
- Italy
  - Anonymous., 9 (Box 27)
  - Miscellaneous Artists, A-Z., 120
    - Allori, Alessandro, 1535-1607., 1 (Box 27)
    - Altichieri, Altichiero, c.1320-1385., 1 (Box 27)
    - Andrea da Firenze, active 1388-1453., 1 (Box 27)
    - Antonella da Messina, 1422-1479., 1 (Box 27)
    - Barna da Siena, 1369-1380., 2 (Box 27)
    - Barocci, Federico, 1526-1612., 1 (Box 27)
    - Bartolo, Domenico di, 1400-1447., 1 (Box 27)
    - Bartolommeo, Fra, 1473-1517., 3 (Box 27)
    - Bassano, Jacopo, 1510-1592., 1 (Box 27)
    - Bassano da Ponte, Leandro, 1557-1622., 1 (Box 27)
    - Bellotto, Bernardo, 1697-1768., 2 (Box 27)
      Also known as Canaletto.
    - Benvenuto di Giovanni, 1436-1518., 1 (Box 27)
    - Bissolo, Francesco, 1492-1554., 1 (Box 27)
    - Boccioni, Umberto, 1882-1916., 1 (Box 27)
    - Bordone, Paris, 1500-1570/1., 1 (Box 27)
    - Botticini, 1446-1497., 1 (Box 27)
      Also known as Francesco di Giovanni.
    - Bronzino, Agnolo, 1502-1573., 1 (Box 27)
    - Cairo, Francesco del, 1598-1674., 1 (Box 28)
    - Canova, Antonio, 1757-1822., 1 (Box 28)
    - Caravaggio, 1571-1610., 3 (Box 28)
    - Caracci, Annibale, 1560-1609., 2 (Box 28)
    - Caracci, Ludovico, 1555-1619., 1 (Box 28)
    - Castagno, Andrea del, 1390-1457., 2 (Box 28)
    - Castiglione, Giovanni Benedetto, 1616-1670., 1 (Box 28)
    - Catena, Vincenzo, 1470-1531., 1 (Box 28)
    - Cavallini, Pietro, active 1250-1330., 1 (Box 28)
    - Chirico, Giorgio de, 1888-1978., 1 (Box 28)
    - Cime de Conegliano, 1459-1517., 1 (Box 28)
    - Cimabue, 1240-1301., 1 (Box 28)
    - Conti, Fernardino de', c.1470-active 1522., 1 (Box 28)
    - Cortona, Pietro da, 1596-1669., 2 (Box 28)
    - Credi, Lorenzo di, 1459-1534., 2 (Box 28)
    - Crivelli, Carlo, 1430/5-1493/5., 1 (Box 28)
    - Crivelli, Vittorio, active 1480-1501., 1 (Box 28)
    - Daddi, Bernardo, active 1328-1350., 1 (Box 28)
    - Dolci, Carlo, 1616-1686., 1 (Box 28)
    - Dossi, Dosso, 1479-1542., 1 (Box 28)
    - Foppa, Vincenzo, 1425-1516., 1 (Box 28)
    - Francesco di Giorgio, 1439-1502., 1 (Box 28)
    - Il Francia, Francesco, 1450-1517., 1 (Box 28)
    - Gentile da Fabriano, 1360-1427., 1 (Box 28)
    - Gentilleschi, Orazio, 1562-1647., 1 (Box 28)
    - Girlandaio, Ridolfo, 1483-1561., 1 (Box 28)
    - Giorgione, 1478-1510., 3 (Box 28)
    - Giovanni da Milano, active 1366., 1 (Box 28)
    - Giovanni di Paolo, 1403-1482., 1 (Box 28)
    - Jacopo del Casentino, 1279-1358., 1 (Box 29)
    - Lambertini, Michel de Matteo, active 1440-1469., 2 (Box 29)
    - Lippi, Filippino, 1457-1504., 3 (Box 29)
    - Longhi, Pietro, 1702-1762., 1 (Box 29)
    - Luini, Bernardino, c.1465-c.1531., 4 (Box 29)
    - Magini, Carlo, 1720-1806., 1 (Box 29)
    - Mancini, Antonio, 1852-1930., 1 (Box 29)
    - Martino di Bartolommeo, active c.1387-1434., 1 (Box 29)
    - Melozzo da Forli, c.1438-1494., 2 (Box 29)
    - Modigliani, Amadeo, 1884-1920., 2 (Box 29)
    - Monsu Desiderio, active 1617-1631., 3 (Box 29)
    - Montagna, Bartolommeo, 1450-1523., 1 (Box 29)
    - Moretto da Brescia, 1498-1554/5., 1 (Box 29)
    - Pannini, Giovanni Paolo, 1691-1765., 1 (Box 29)
    - Parmigianino, 1503-1540., 1 (Box 29)
    - Piazetta, Giovanni Battista, 1682-1754., 3 (Box 29)
    - Piero di Cosimo, 1462-c.1521., 1 (Box 29)
    - Pisanello, 1395-1455., 2 (Box 29)
    - Pollaiuolo, Antonio, 1433-1498., 2 (Box 29)
    - Procaccini, ??., 1 (Box 29)
    - Reni, Guido, 1575-1642., 3 (Box 30)
    - Salvi, Giovanni Battista, 1609-1685., 1 (Box 30)
    - Salviati, Francesco il, 1510-1563., 1 (Box 30)
    - San Leocadio, Paolo da, active 1472-c.1513., 1 (Box 30)
    - Sano di Pietro, 1406-1481., 1 (Box 30)
    - Santomaso, Guiseppe, 1907-., 1 (Box 30)
    - Sarto, Andrea del, 1486-1531., 4 (Box 30)
    - Sassetta, Stefano di Giovanni, 1392-1450., 2 (Box 30)
    - Savoldo, Giovanni Girolamo, c.1480-1548., 1 (Box 30)
    - Simone Martini, 1283-1344., 3 (Box 30)
    - Squarcione, Francesco, 1394-1474., 1 (Box 30)
    - Traini, Francesco, active 1320-1364., 2 (Box 30)
    - Veneziano, Domenico, 1400-1461., 2 (Box 30)
    - Verocchio, Andrea del, 1435-1488., 3 (Box 30)
    - Vitale da Bologna, XIV C., 1 (Box 30)
    - Utili, Giovanni Battista, active 1495-1516., 1 (Box 30)
      Also known as Giovanni Battista Bertucci the Elder.
  - Individual Artists, A-Z., 505
    - Angelico, Fra, 1387-1455., 10 (Box 31)
    - Bellini, Giovanni, 1428/30-1516., 9 (Box 31)
    - Benozzo Gozzoli, 1420-1497., 8 (Box 31)
    - Botticelli, Sandro, 1445-1510., 19 (Box 32)
    - Canal, Antonio, 1697-1768., 5 (Box 32)
    - Carpaccio, Vittore, 1455-1525., 6 (Box 32)
    - Correggio, Antonio Allegri, 1494-1534., 7 (Box 32)
    - Duccio di Buoninsegna, 1255-1319., 5 (Box 33)
    - Francesco, Piero della, 1416-1492., 20 (Box 33)
    - Ghirlandaio, Domenico, 1449-1495., 10 (Box 33)
    - Giotto, 1266-1337., 10 (Box 34)
    - Guardi, Franceso de', 1712-1793., 5 (Box 34)
    - Laurana, Luciano, 1420/25-1479., 10 (Box 34)
    - Leonardo da Vinci, 1453-1519., 20 (Box 35)
    - Lippi, Fra Filippino, 1457-1504., 4 (Box 35)
    - Lorenzetti, Ambrogio, c.1319-1348., 8 (Box 35)
    - Lorenzetti, Pietro, active 1280-1348., 4 (Box 36)
    - Mantegna, Andrea, 1431-1506., 9 (Box 36)
    - Masaccio, Tomasso Giudi, 1401-1428., 5 (Box 36)
    - Michelangelo Buonarotti, 1475-1564., 195
      - Drawings., 24 (Box 37)
      - Paintings., 171
        - Florence., 3 (Box 37)
        - London., 5 (Box 37)
        - Rome., 163
          - Miscellaneous works., 4 (Box 38)
          - Last Judgement., 25 (Box 38)
          - Sistine Ceiling., 134
            - General views., 27 (Box 39)
            - Creation of man., 10 (Box 40)
            - Creation of the sun and moon., 7 (Box 40)
            - Creation of the waters and earth., 3 (Box 40)
            - Creation of woman., 6 (Box 40)
            - Decorative figures., 29 (Box 41)
            - Deluge., 7 (Box 42)
            - Expulsion., 4 (Box 42)
            - Prophets., 23 (Box 42)
            - Sybils., 18 (Box 43)
    - Nardo di Cione, active 1343-1355/6., 13 (Box 43)
    - Orcagno, Andrea di Cione, 1308-1368., 1 (Box 44)
    - Perugino, Pietro, 1446-1523., 4 (Box 44)
    - Pinturicchio, Bernardo, 1454-1513., 6 (Box 44)
    - Pontormo, Jacopo da, 1494-1557., 6 (Box 44)
    - Raphael Sanzio, 1483-1520., 54 (Box 45–46)
    - Signorelli, Luca, 1441-1523., 7 (Box 47)
    - Sodoma, Giovanni, 1477-1549., 4 (Box 47)
    - Tiepolo, Giovanni Battista, 1696-1770., 7 (Box 47)
    - Tintoretto, Jacopo, 1518-1594., 11 (Box 47)
    - Titian, 1477-1576., 9 (Box 48)
    - Uccello, Paolo, 1397-1475., 5 (Box 48)
    - Veronese, Paolo, 1528-1588., 9 (Box 48)
- Russia (Box 49)
  - Anonymous., 6 (Box 49)
  - Miscellaneous Artists, A-Z., 7 (Box 49)
    - Chagall, Marc, 1889-1985., 2 (Box 49)
    - Delaunay-Terk, Sonia, 1885-1979., 1 (Box 49)
    - Kandinsky, Vasily, 1866-1944., 1 (Box 49)
    - Malevich, Kasimir, 1878-1935., 1 (Box 49)
    - Rublev, Andrei, 1370-1430., 1 (Box 49)
    - Segall, Lasar, 1891-1957., 1 (Box 49)
- Spain
  - Anonymous., 3 (Box 49)
  - Miscellaneous Artists, A-Z., 21
    - Antolinez, Jose, 1639-1676., 1 (Box 49)
    - Berruguete, Pedro, c.1450-c.1504., 1 (Box 49)
    - Blas del Prado, 1497-1447., 1 (Box 49)
    - Cabezalero, Juan Martin, 1633-1673., 1 (Box 49)
    - Cerezo, Matteo, 1635-1685., 1 (Box 49)
    - Coello, Claudio, 1621-1693., 1 (Box 49)
    - Collantes, Francisco, 1599-1656., 1 (Box 49)
    - El Greco, 1541-1614., 3 (Box 49)
    - Herrera, Francisco the Elder, 1576-1656., 1 (Box 49)
    - Leonardo, Jusepe, 1616-1656., 1 (Box 49)
    - Pareja, Juan, 1606-1670., 1 (Box 49)
    - Pradilla y Ortiz, Francisco, 1847-1921., 2 (Box 49)
    - Ribera, Jusepe de, 1588-1656., 3 (Box 49)
    - Rizi, Fray Juan, 1595-1675., 1 (Box 49)
    - Solana, Jose Gutierrez, 1886-1945., 1 (Box 49)
    - Valdes Leal, Juan de, 1622-1690., 1 (Box 49)
  - Individual Artists, A-Z., 89
    - Goya, Francisco, 1746-1828., 31 (Box 50)
    - Miro, Joan, 1893-1983., 8 (Box 51)
    - Murillo, Bartolome Esteban, 1618-1682., 20 (Box 51)
    - Picasso, Pablo, 1881-1973., 10 (Box 52)
    - Velasquez, Diego, 1599-1660., 17 (Box 52)
    - Zurbaran, Francisco de, 1598-1662., 3 (Box 52)
- Sweden (Box 53)
  - Miscellaneous Artists, A-Z., 1 (Box 53)
    - Fahlstrom, Oyvind, 1928-., 1 (Box 53)
- Switzerland (Box 53)
  - Miscellaneous Artists, A-Z., 5 (Box 53)
    - Agasse, Jacques-Laurent, 1767-1849., 1 (Box 53)
    - Amiet, Cuno, 1868-1961., 1 (Box 53)
    - Asper, Hans, 1499-1571., 1 (Box 53)
    - Hodler, Ferdinand, 1853-1918., 1 (Box 53)
    - Vallotton, Felix, 1865-1925., 1 (Box 53)
  - Individual Artists, A-Z., 8 (Box 53)
    - Klee, Paul, 1879-1940., 8 (Box 53)
- Yugoslavia (Box 53)
  - Anonymous., 2 (Box 53)
- United States
  - Miscellaneous Artists, A-Z., 100
    - Abbey, Edwin Austin, 1852-1911., 1 (Box 54)
    - Allston, Washington, 1779-1840., 1 (Box 54)
    - Bellows, George, 1860-1925., 1 (Box 54)
    - Benton, Thomas Hart, 1889-1975., 1 (Box 54)
    - Bierstadt, Albert, 1830-1902., 3 (Box 54)
    - Bingham, George Caleb, 1811-1879., 1 (Box 54)
    - Cassatt, Mary, 1845-1926., 1 (Box 54)
    - Church, Frederic E., 1826-1900., 1 (Box 54)
    - Cole, Thomas, 1801-1848., 1 (Box 54)
    - Colman, Samuel, 1832-1920., 1 (Box 54)
    - Copley, John Singleton, 1737-1815., 2 (Box 54)
    - Curry, John Steuart, 1897-1946., 1 (Box 54)
    - Davies, Arthur B., 1862-1928., 1 (Box 54)
    - Davis, Stuart, 1894-1964., 1 (Box 54)
    - De Kooning, Willem, 1904-., 2 (Box 54)
    - Downes, Rackstraw, 1939-., 2 (Box 54)
    - Eakins, Thomas, 1844-1916., 2 (Box 54)
    - Ehniger, John Whetton, 1827-1889., 1 (Box 54)
    - Field, Erastus Salisbury, 1805-1900., 1 (Box 54)
    - Fischl, Eric, 1948-., 1 (Box 54)
    - Fish, Janet, 1938-., 1 (Box 54)
    - Francis, Sam, 1923-., 1 (Box 54)
    - Frankenthaler, Helen, 1928-., 1 (Box 54)
    - Freilicher, Jane, 1924-., 1 (Box 54)
    - Golub, Leon, 1922-., 1 (Box 54)
    - Gorky, Arshile, 1904-1948., 1 (Box 54)
    - Hassam, Childe, 1859-1935., 1 (Box 54)
    - Henry, Edward L., 1841-1919., 1 (Box 54)
    - Homer, Winslow, 1836-1910., 6 (Box 54)
    - Hopper, Edward, 1882-1967., 2 (Box 54)
    - Katz, Alex, 1927-., 1 (Box 54)
    - Komar & Melamid, XX C., 1 (Box 54)
    - Krasner, Lee, 1911-., 1 (Box 54)
    - Lane, Fitz Hugh, 1804-1865., 1 (Box 54)
    - Lebrun, Rico, 1900-., 1 (Box 54)
    - Liberman, Alexander, 1912-., 1 (Box 54)
    - Lindner, Richard, 1901-., 1 (Box 54)
    - Marsh, Reginald, 1894-1955., 2 (Box 55)
    - Metcalf, W. L., 1858-1925., 1 (Box 55)
    - Miller, Alfred J., 1810-1874., 1 (Box 55)
    - Mitchell, Joan, 1926-1992., 1 (Box 55)
    - Morse, Samuel F. B., 1791-1872., 1 (Box 55)
    - Mount, William Sidney, 1807-1868., 2 (Box 55)
    - O'Keeffe, Georgia, 1887-1986., 5 (Box 55)
    - Parrish, Maxfield, 1870-1966., 1 (Box 55)
    - Peale, Rembrandt, 1778-1860., 1 (Box 55)
    - Pollock, Jackson, 1912-1956., 1 (Box 55)
    - Pousette-Dart, Richard, 1916-., 1 (Box 55)
    - Resnick, Milton, 1917-., 1 (Box 55)
    - Rosler, Martha, 1943-., 1 (Box 55)
    - Rothko, Mark, 1903-1970., 2 (Box 55)
    - Ryder, Albert Pinkham, 1847-1917., 2 (Box 55)
    - Salle, David, 1952-., 1 (Box 55)
    - Salmon, Robert W., c.1829-1840., 1 (Box 55)
    - Sargent, John Singer, 1856-1925., 6 (Box 55)
    - Shinn, Everett, 1876-1953., 1 (Box 55)
    - Sloan, John, 1871-1951., 1 (Box 55)
    - Smibert, John, 1684-1751., 1 (Box 55)
    - Still, Clyfford, 1904-., 1 (Box 55)
    - Stuart, Gilbert, 1755-1828., 2 (Box 55)
    - Tchelitchew, Pavel, 1898-., 1 (Box 56)
    - Tworkov, Jack, 1902-., 1 (Box 56)
    - Weir, John Ferguson, 1841-1926., 2 (Box 56)
    - West, Benjamin, 1738-1820., 1 (Box 56)
    - Wood, Grant, 1892-1942., 7 (Box 56)
    - Wood, Thomas W., 1823-1903., 1 (Box 56)
    - Worse, Theodore, 1860-1939., 1 (Box 56)
- Mexico (Box 57)
  - Anonymous., 2 (Box 57)
  - Miscellaneous Artists, A-Z., 13 (Box 57)
    - Arteaga, Sepastian Lopez de, 1610-1653., 1 (Box 57)
    - Atl, Dr., 1875-1964., 1 (Box 57)
    - Echave Orio, Baltasar de, c.1585-c.1645., 1 (Box 57)
    - Herrera, Alonzo Lopez de, 1579-c.1654., 1 (Box 57)
    - Juarez, Jose, c.1615-1667., 1 (Box 57)
    - Pereyns, Simon, active 1566-1586., 1 (Box 57)
    - Rivera, Diego, 1886-1957., 4 (Box 57)
    - Siqueiros, David, 1898-1974., 2 (Box 57)
    - Tamayo, Rufino, 1900-., 1 (Box 57)